Finding aid to Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women records SSC.MS.00584
Sophia Smith Collection
Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women records
1962-2009
Sophia Smith Collection
Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women
SSC.MS.00584
31.875 linear feet (39 containers)
The Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women records contain administrative records related to women's collegiate athletics in the 1970s and 1980s, including records of anti-trust litigation with the NCAA and AIAW's advocacy for parity in women's sports. The records also include materials pertaining to AIAW's management of high school and collegiate women's sports, including coaches' handbooks, brochures, and event programs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Margot Polivy and Leotus Morrison donated the collection to Smith College in 2007 and 2009 respectively.
Arrangement
The collection has been left in the same order it was in when it came to Smith Special Collections. Similar material is often grouped together, but no attempt has been made to reoder files.
Biographical Note
The Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women was founded in 1971 to govern collegiate women's athletics in the United States and to administer national championships. It evolved out of the Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (founded in 1967). Through the 1970s, the AIAW grew rapidly in membership and influence, in parallel with the national growth of women's sports following the enactment of Title IX. The AIAW functioned in the equivalent role for college women's programs that the NCAA had been doing for men's programs. Due in part to its own success, the AIAW ended up in conflicts with the NCAA in the early 1980s. Following a one-year overlap in which both organizations staged women's championships, the AIAW discontinued operation and most member schools continued their women's athletics programs under the governance of the NCAA.
Related Materials
Eastern Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women, Massachusetts Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women Records
Scope and Contents
Records contain administrative files, including records of the Board of Directors; files documenting the AIAW's advocacy for parity in women's sports (Title IX controversy and other legislative inititatives, including passage of the Amateur Sports Act); AIAW involvement with other sports organizations, both national and international; coaches' manuals and other printed materials pertaining to women's high school and college sports; legal and administrative correspondence; legal files re: litigation in which the AIAW was involved, including the AIAW/NCAA anti-trust lawsuit; files pertaining to the AIAW-NBC television contract; and to the decision to terminate operations of the AIAW.
Women in sports; Sports -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History -- Sources; Agendas; DVD video discs; Bylaws; Legal files; Manuals; Minutes; Organization files; Sports for women--History--20th century-Sources; Constitutions; Sports for women--Organization and administration--History--Sources; Annual reports; Legal documents; Financial records; correspondence; Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women; Morrison, Leotus; Polivy, Margot; Morrison, Leotus; Polivy, Margot
- Promotions Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee -- Meeting, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee -- Presidents' Files, 1975-1978 (Box 1)
- Rules Standards Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
- Delegate Assembly, 1978 (Box 1)
- Ethics and Eligibility (E & E) Committee -- Meetings, 1978 (Box 1)
- Executive Board -- Meeting, 1978 (Box 1)
- Executive Board -- Student Leadership Conference, 1978 (Box 1)
- Women's Athletic Directors' Conference, Atlanta, 1978 (Box 1)
- Women's Pro Basketball League (WBL) -- Basketball Championship meeting, University of California- Los Angeles, 1978 (Box 1)
- Eastern Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (EAIAW) -- Meetings, Providence, RI, 1978 (Box 1)
- American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, and Recreation (AAHPER) Convention, 1978 (Box 1)
- U.S. Collegiate Sports Council (USCSC) meeting, 1978 (Box 1)
- Executive Board meeting, 1978 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee meeting, 1978 (Box 2)
- Athletic Directors Conference, 1979 (Box 2)
- E &E meetings, 1979 (Box 2)
- Executive Board meetings, 1979-01 (Box 2)
- Delegate Assembly, 1979-01 (Box 2)
- Student Leadership Conference, 1979-01 (Box 2)
- Executive Board meeting, 1979-05 (Box 2)
- Boston- Bouvé College: Administration of Women Collegiate Athletic Programs: workshops, 1979-06 (Box 2)
- National Women's Political Caucus (NWPC) Convention, Cincinnati, OH, 1979-07 (Box 2)
- University of Iowa: Workshop in Sport Studies, 1979-07 (Box 2)
- Executive Board meeting, 1979-10 (Box 2)
- Women Shaping Tomorrow Conference: Madison College, Harrisonburg, VA, 1979-11 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Alabama State University, 1977-04 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- University of South Alabama, 1977-04 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Temple University, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Augsburg College Law Suit, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Liberty Baptist College, 1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Marshall University, 1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- McNeese State University, 1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Montana College of Mineral Science & Technology, 1977-12 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Shaw College at Detroit, 1977-02 (Box 2)
- AIAW Membership -- Talladega College, 1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Organizational -- Association of American Colleges (AAC): Project on Status of Women, 1972-1977 (Box 2)
- AIAW Organizational -- American Association for Health Physical Education and Recreation (AAHPER): actions regarding the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1975 (Box 2)
- AIAW Organizational -- AAHPER: non-litigation; pre-client materials, 1973-1976 (Box 2)
- AIAW Organizational -- AIAW/AAHPER relationship, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
- AIAW Organizational -- AAHPER/ AIAW/ National Association for Girls & Women in Sport (NAGWS), 1974-1980 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- AAHPER: Sanity in Sport, 1976-11 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- AIAW/ AAHPER relationship: AAHPER materials, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Commercial endorsements, 1977 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Executive Board, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Executive Secretary Search, 1977 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Handbook, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Handbook & Regulations, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Handbook, 1975-1980 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Hanes/Medalist BB Classic, 1978 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Judith R. Holland, 1978 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Member Mailing List, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- Medalist Industries, Inc., 1978 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition: Califano Meeting, 1977 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition: Civil Rights Coalition, 1975-1979 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition: Civil Rights Reorg., 1979 (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational (continued) -- National Coalition: Comments and Testimony (Box 3)
- AIAW Organizational (continued) -- National Coalition: General, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
- AIAW Organizational (continued) -- National Coalition: Committee to Examine Proper Focuses for Title IX, 1977 (Box 4)
- AIAW Organizational (continued) -- National Women's Agenda, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW): Draft Policies, 1978-12 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Draft Policies: Comments, 1978-12 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Draft Policies: General, 1978-12 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Draft Policies: Legislation, 1978-12 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Draft Policies/Interpretations, 1973-1978 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Relations: Athletics, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Relations: General, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
- AIAW -- Ghostings & Position Memoranda, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- HEW Relations: General, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
- ALAW Title IX Administration, HEW Draft Policies Background/Clippings, 1978-12 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- Office of Civil Rights (OCR) Proposed 1977 Operating Plan (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- OCR Proposed 1978 Operating Plan (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- OCR Reorganization (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- Procedural Regulations Proposed, 1976-05 (Box 5)
- AIAW Title IX Administration -- Comments on Proposed Regulations, 1974-1979 (Box 5)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- General, 1976-08-1979 (Box 5)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- Executive Board Meeting: Dallas, Texas, 1979-11 (Box 5)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- Executive Board Meeting, 1978 (Box 5)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- House of Delegates Meeting, 1979-04 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- House of Delegates and Committees Meetings: Florida, 1978-04 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- House of Delegates: Florida, 1978-04 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics: USOC -- Legislation Committee (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- President's Commission on Olympic Sports: Legislative Drafts, 1977 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- President's Commission on Olympic Sports: General, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- President's Commission on Olympic Sports: Public Hearings, 1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- Australian Tour, 1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- Background, 1975-1979 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- Chinese Basketball Tour: General, 1975-11 (Box 6)
- AIAW International Athletics -- Chinese Basketball Tour: Internal, 1975-11 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation Files List (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation -- Academic Freedom Act of 1979 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation -- Buckley Amendment, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Butler Amendment, 1979 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Civil Rights Attorneys' Fees Act, 1975 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Department of Education, 1979 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA), 1978 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Handicapped Section 504 Regulations, 1977 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Higher Education Bill: Text, 1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Higher Education Bill: Amendments, 1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Higher Education Bill: Buckley Amendment, 1976 (Box 6)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Labor HEW Appropriations, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Title VII Amendments, 1977 (Box 7)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Title IX Regulations: O'Hara Hearings, 1975 (Box 7)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Tower Amendment, 1974 (Box 7)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Tower Bill, 1975 (Box 7)
- AIAW Legislation (continued) -- Vocational Education, 1976 (Box 7)
- AIAW Meetings -- Delegate Assembly, 1982 (Box 7)
- AIAW Meetings -- Executive Committee, 1982-03-26 (Box 7)
- AIAW Meetings -- USOC, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- 14th National Conference on Women and the Law, 1983-04 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Delegate Assembly, 1980-1982 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board, 1982-04 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Ethics and Eligibility (E&E) Committee Meeting, 1980-01 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- E&E Meeting, 1980-03 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board Meeting, 1980-01 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Committee Meetings, 1980 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Women's AD Conference, 1980-01 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board Meeting, 1980-05 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Athletic Congress Convention, 1980-06-08-1980-06-10 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Committee, 1980-06 (Box 7)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- E&E Committee, Denver, CO, 1980-09 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Law of Sports: Syracuse University, 1980-09 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Aid Conference, Wooster, OH, 1980-11 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Centenary College of Louisiana - Workshop, 1980-07 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Delegate Assembly, 1982 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board, 1980-10 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Title IX Conference, Atlanta, GA, 1980-12 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board, 1981-01 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Strategy Planning Re. NCAA, 1981 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- AIAW/NCAA Meeting, 1981-04 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board, 1981-05 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- E&E Meeting, 1981-08 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Committee, 1981-09 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Board, 1981-10 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Executive Committee, 1982-01 (Box 8)
- AIAW meetings (continued) -- Membership: Actives and Associates, 1980-1982 (Box 8)
- AIAW Membership -- General, 1975-1981 (Box 8)
- AIAW Membership -- Kentucky Wesleyan College, 1979 (Box 8)
- AIAW Membership -- Middlebury College, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
- AIAW Membership -- Middlebury College: extra Copies (Box 8)
- AIAW Informational -- Background, News Clippings, and Articles, 1975-1978 (Box 8)
- AIAW Promotional -- Madison Square Garden, 1977-1999 (Box 8)
- AIAW Promotional -- Rawlings Sporting Goods Company, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
- AIAW Promotional (continued) -- Contracts File (Box 9)
- AIAW Promotional (continued) -- Licensing Proposal, 1980 (Box 9)
- AIAW Correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 9)
- AIAW Organizational -- Letters of Intent, 1975-1978 (Box 10)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition: General, 1979 (Box 10)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition, 1980 (Box 10)
- AIAW Organizational -- National Coalition: Mathews Meeting, 1975-12 (Box 10)
- AIAW Organizational -- Peer (Box 10)
- AIAW Organizational -- President's Conference (Box 10)
- AIAW International Athletics -- USOC Legislation Committee, 1979-04 (Box 10)
- AIAW International Athletics -- USOC Materials (Box 10)
- AIAW Ethics and Eligibility -- General, 1974-1980 (Box 11)
- AIAW Ethics and Eligibility -- Institutional Files, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Background and Clippings, 1975-1981 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Film, 1975-1981 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Journalism, 1976-78, 1976-1978 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Legal Problems Re Media Coverage, 1975-1976 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Radio, 1977-1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Revenue Agreements, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Television: Member Contracting, 1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Television: High Bar Productions, 1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Television: Sugarman, 1976-1980 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Television: TVS, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media -- Television: Thompson Communications Inc., 1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media (continued) -- Television: Total Communication Systems, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media (continued) -- AIAW/WHRO-TV, 1979 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media (continued) -- Television: Communications Re Particular Events, 1975-1981 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media (continued) -- Television: Communications – General, 1974-1981 (Box 11)
- AIAW Media (continued) -- Television: ESPN, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
- AIAW Handbook - Directory, 1975-1979 (Box 12)
- AIAW Directory, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
- Ethics and Eligibility Casebook, 1980-1981 (Box 12)
- Competitive Division Structure Implementation Survey: Final Data Summary, 1978 (Box 12)
- AIAW Handbooks, 1973-1981 (Box 12)
- Coaches' Manuals: Indoor Track & Field, Tennis, Skiing, Badminton, Basketball, Cross-Country, Softball, 1980-1982 (Box 12)
- Coaches' Manuals: Fencing, Field Hockey, Golf, Gymnastics, Lacrosse, Rowing, Outdoor Track & Field, Swimming & Diving, Synch. Swimming, Volleyball, 1980-1982 (Box 12)
- AIAW National Championships - General (Box 12)
- Brochures and Programs, 1974-1979 (Box 12)
- AIAW Meetings — List of Closed Documents and Meetings (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Executive Board, 1972-1974 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Miscellaneous Board Meetings, 1975 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Women's Athletic Directors Workshop – Big Sky Montana, 1979-05 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Bozeman Think-Tank – Montana State University, 1979-10 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Executive Board, 1975-1977 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- E&E Committee, 1977-01 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Delegate Assembly, 1977-01 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- 3rd Delegate Assembly, 1976-01 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- Workshop – Boone N.C., 1975-08 (Box 13)
- AIAW Meetings -- 2nd Delegate Assembly, 1975-01 (Box 13)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Defendant's Exhibits A-XXX (Box 14)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Plaintiff's Exhibits #1-28 (Box 14)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Plaintiff's Exhibits #29-75 (Box 14)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Plaintiff's Exhibits #76-132 (Box 14)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Plaintiff's Exhibits #133-199 (Box 14)
- Exhibits 22, 23, 31, 185 (Box 14)
- Exhibits 24, 25, 28, 35, 36 (Box 14)
- Exhibits 1, 2, 26, 27 (Box 14)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T16 – Berkey Deposition, 1980-04 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T15 – Byers Deposition, 1980-04 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T14 – Judith Holland Deposition, 1982-03 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T12 – Lardner Deposition, 1982-03 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- D. Lopiano Deposition, 1982-01 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T6 – Lopiano Deposition, 1982-02 (Box 15)
- G. Mason Telephone Conversation, 1982-04 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- G. Ann Uhlir Depositions, 1982-01 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T7 – Uhlir Deposition, 1982-02 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T11 – Watson Deposition, 1982-03 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- T13 – John Toner Deposition, 1982-03 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Depositions (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Defendant's Exhibits A-ZZ (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Defendant's Exhibits AAA-XXX (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation — AIAW v. NCAA — Exhibit 183: National Assoc. of Intercollegiate Athletics — Official Handbook (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation — AIAW v. NCAA — Exhibits 13, 14, 17, 186 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation — AIAW v. NCAA — Exhibits 12, 16, 18, 20, 21 (Box 15)
- AIAW Litigation — Exhibits 3, 4 (Box 15)
- AIAW Committees: TV Committee, 1976-1980 (Box 16)
- Court Transcript: Mimi Murray Affidavit (Box 16)
- Defendant's Exhibits (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Merrily Baker (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Chris Grant (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Ginny Hunt (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Donna Lopiano (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Mimi Murray (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Carole Mushier (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Bonnie Slatton (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Jeffrey Cokin (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Rex Lardner (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Don Ohlmeyer (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Ken Schanzer (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Stephen Ulrich (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Arthur Watson (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Donald Wear (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- NBC Depositions from NCAA case (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Originals (Box 16)
- AIAW v. NBC Depositions -- Extras (Box 16)
- NBC Contract – Basketball & Gymnastics National Championships, 1978 (Box 16)
- AIAW Organizational: Budget and Finance (Box 16)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Appendix to Lopiano Affidavit (Box 17)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume I, Part 1, 1981 (Box 17)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume I, Part 2 (Box 17)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume I, Part 3 (Box 18)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume II, #28-#65 (Box 18)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume III, #66-#107 (Box 18)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume IV, #108-#117 (Box 18)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume V, #118-#140 (Box 18)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume VI, #141-#159 (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Chron. File: Volume VII, #160-#190 (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Appeal – Chron. File: Volume VIII, #198- (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Trial – Main File: Volume I, #1-#140 (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Trial – Main File: Volume II, #141-#159 (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Trial – Main File: Volume III (Box 19)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: appeal (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: transcripts -- Index (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- #1 Status Call, 1981-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- #2 Status Call, 1981-12 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- Status Call Transcript, 1982-02 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T8 – Status Call Excerpt, 1982-02 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- Status Call, 1982-03 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T20 – Trial Transcript, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T21 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T22 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T23 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T24 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T25 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T26 – Trial Transcripts, 1982-10-29 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: Transcripts (continued) -- T27 – Closing Argument Transcript, 1983-02-17 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Brief for Appellant (2 copies), 1983-08 (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA -- Record Excerpts: Volumes I & II (Box 20)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Communications with Press/Members (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Discovery – Depositions (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Discovery – Main File (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Discovery – Requests and Responses (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Stipulations (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Settlement (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Preliminary Injunction – Main File (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Preliminary Injunction – Cir. Appeal (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA (continued) -- Expert witness (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Berkey (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Byers (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Cerra (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Finch (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Frank (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Holland (Box 21)
- AIAW Litigation – AIAW v. NCAA: NCAA Testimony -- Klein (Box 21)